If bad people hurt someone you love, how far would you go to hurt them back?
The Last House on the Left is a crime, thriller,
horror film directed by Dennis Iliadis.
When athletic teen Mari Collingwood opts to hang out with her friend Paige in town rather than spend an evening in with her
parents vacationing at the family's remote lake house, it marks the beginning of a night no one is going to forget.
John Collingwood, played by Tony Goldwyn.
Emma Collingwood, played by Monica Potter.
Mari Collingwood, played by Sara Paxton.
Krug, played by Garret Dillahunt.
Francis, played by Aaron Paul.
Justin, played by Spencer Treat Clark.
The Last House on the Left is a 2009 rape and revenge film directed by
Dennis Iliadis and written by Adam Alleca and Carl Ellsworth.
A remake of the 1972 film of the same name, it stars Tony Goldwyn, Monica Potter, Garret Dillahunt,
Aaron Paul, Spencer Treat Clark, Riki Lindhome, Martha MacIsaac, and Sara Paxton.
The film follows Mari Collingwood, a teenager who is abducted, raped,
and left for dead by a family of violent fugitives.
When her parents learn what was done to her, they seek vengeance against the family,
who have taken shelter at their summer home during a thunderstorm.
The rights to The Last House on the Left were picked up by Rogue Pictures in 2006, with the remake
being the first film produced by Craven's newly formed studio Midnight Pictures.
Craven, who wrote and directed the original film, was interested to see what kind of film could be made on a larger
budget, as the limited funds forced him to remove scenes he had wanted to film to tell a complete story.
One of the elements Iliadis wanted to avoid with the film, given its
graphic nature, was turning it into "torture porn".
For Craven and Iliadis, the film primarily illustrates how even the most normal
of families can be driven to commit evil acts if pushed too far.
The original script by Alleca included elements of supernatural horror, which
prompted the studio to reject it and bring in Ellsworth for rewrites.
Principal photography began in March 2008 in Cape Town and
Helderberg Nature Reserve and concluded in May.
The Last House on the Left was theatrically released in the United States on March 13, 2009, and was
a modest box office success, grossing $46 million against its $15 million budget.
The film received mixed reviews from critics, with several deeming it worthy of praise in comparison to
other horror films and remakes in general, while others considered it inferior to the original.
The film explores themes of lake, rape, kidnapping, psychopath, sadistic.
The tone is lighthearted and dark and emotional.